你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing down here?
我以为你喜欢和昏迷病人一起用午餐
I thought you usually,had lunch with coma guy.
这是个植物人, 比昏迷病人还好
This is vegetative state guy.,Better company.
跟他说说那些夏尔巴人怎么和你一起在,圣帕特里克大教堂里吃迷幻药,(夏尔巴人信佛教)
Hey, tell him about those sherpas,you dropped acid within st.Patrick's cathedral.
你偷了我的处方,伪造我的签名
You stole my prescription pad,,and you forged my name.
- 你怎么和警察说的?,- 我说了谎
- What did you tell the cop?,- I lied.
他们会把你抓去坐十年的牢
They'd have put you away for ten years.
还会吊销你的行医执照
After they took your license,to practice medicine.
- 也就是说没事了,- 我向警察说谎了
- So everything's good, then.,- I lied to the cops.
除非能证明我非法买卖药品,否则没法起诉我
There is no case unless they can prove that either,I gotthe drugs illegally or I sold them illegally.
我没贩卖, 你还替我圆了谎,没事了
I didn't do the second.,You lied about the first. Game over.
是啊, Tritter只是玩玩而已
Yeah.,Tritter's just playing.
他就想看看你有多聪明,然后拍拍屁股走人
He's gonna seehow clever you are,and then just walk away.
重要的是你得继续保持,开药的分量不变
The important thing is that you keep,prescribing the same amount of drugs to me,
否则就很可疑了
or it'll look suspicious.
你应该从这个角度看
Here's another way to look at it.
逼得我向警察说谎以后,你所关心的只是保证继续获得药物
Having forced me to lie to the police,,your first concern is securing your drug connection.
和我父亲一起共进午餐?
Joining my father for lunch?
我事先该定个桌子
I should've called ahead for a table.
- House医生只是在...,- 享用牛肉三明治
- Dr. House was just--,- enjoying a reuben.
没关系
It's okay.
都十年了 不论什么原因只要有医生,还愿意进这个房间..
After ten years, anything that'll,get doctorsin the same room as--
- 你做什么?,- 没什么
- what are you doing?,- Nothing.
你在干吗?
What are you doing?
薯片?
Chips?
想听点有趣的事吗?
Wanna see something really cool?
上个星期二我见你离开
I saw you leaving last tuesday.
出去时几乎被两个人绊倒,但开门没什么问题
Practically tripped over two guys on your way out,,but you had no problem opening doors.
这叫运动盲
It's called akinetopsia.
你看不见运动中的物体
You can't see things when they move.
鉴于你还没被车撞过看来,症状应该是间歇性的
And since you haven't been hit by a bus,,I assume that it's intermittent.
还有可能伴有癫痫,所以我才让灯闪来闪去(诱发癫痫)
It's probably accompaniedby seizures,which made me,think that I could set one off by flashing them
上帝, 瞧这一家人!
god, I love this family!
-=豪斯医生=-,S03E07 "Son of Coma Guy"
House,Season 3 Episode 07
我现在看的很清楚
I can see fine now.
我曾犯过癫痫
I've had seizures before.
多数时候都不严重
Most of the time, they're small.
很多医生给我做过全身检查
Doctors ran me through all the tests.
可什么也没查出来
Couldn't find anything.
你的家族有癫痫症史吗?
Any history of epilepsy in your family?
我对我的家族,只记得一大串不知羞耻的事件
The only things I know that,run in my family are a lot of chutzpah
还有老爸长眠不醒的能耐
and the ability to sleep for ten years.
尽管我不是专家
Although i'm not really an expert.
爸爸着实不喜欢妈妈的家人,她去世后他就来这儿了
Dad never really liked my mother's side of the family,,and after she died and he came here,
我是被监护人抚养大的
I was raised by a guardian.
现在也没什么联系了
I wouldn't even know,how to get in touch with him.
那你父亲这边的家人呢?
How 'bout your father's side of the family?
能找个亲戚谈谈吗?
Any relatives we could speak with?
我父亲是独生子
My father was an only child.
而且我的祖父母也过世了
And my grandparents are dead.
那你有紧急情况入院时会联系谁?
Well, who did you put down as the person,the hospital should contact in an emergency?
- 那行我空着了,- 总得有个人, 比如朋友?
- I left it blank.,- there's gotta be someone.A friend?
嗯, 朋友挺多,就是...
Oh, plenty of friends.,Just...
没人会来看我
no one that would care if I was here.
麻烦你把我的背包拿过来好吗?
Say, do you mind passing me my backpack?
遗传的
Hair of the dog.
- 可能是感染,- 或者颅内肿瘤
- could be infection.,- or a brain tumor.
报告说他做过CT了
Says he had a ct.
最简单的解释是什么? 外伤
What's wrong with the,simplest explanation?Trauma.
他没有报告有外伤
He didn't report any injuries.
他也不会报告酗酒
He didn't report,being an alcoholic, either.
酗酒能解释昏厥, 造成外伤,造成...
Drinking equals falling down,,equals trauma, equals
或许是遗传疾病
maybe it's inherited.
你怎么能从脑电图上看出遗传疾病来
How would you jump to,genetics from his eeg?
你只看到了模糊的类似癫痫的波型
All you've got are some,vaguely epileptiform waves.
他的脑电图没事,是他老爸的
It's not his eeg.,It's his father'S.
注意看脑皮层的波形,有其父必有其子
When it comes to cortical seizures,,like father, like son.
当病人处于植物人状态时,轻微中风是有可能的
Small seizures aren't unheard of,in a patient in a vegetative state.
但父子相似还是值得深究
Similarities are interesting, though.
什么导致他成为植物人?
What caused the vegetative state?
他家着了大火
His house burned down.
他跑回妻子的身边
Went back into get his wife.
结果消防员发现他不省人事,在离家门三英尺的地方, 窒息了
Firefighters found him unconscious,three feet from the bedroom, asphyxiated.
根本和遗传无关
Not an inherited condition.
测试他的DNA
Test his dna.
从肾上腺髓质神经病变开始
Start with a drenomyeloneuropathy.
检查他家
Check out the home.
- 他睡单人床,- 这年月还生产单人床?
- He has a single bed.,- They still make single beds?
表明最近没有性行为,可房里有避孕套
Could mean he just doesn't have sex--,though there were condoms in the apartment.
House叫你检查他家的毒素?
House asked you to check out the home for toxins.
没霉菌, 没渗漏, 没宠物
No mold, no leaks, no pets.
MRI和LP并非绝对可靠,仍然存在感染的可能性
mri and lp are both inconclusive.,Infection's still possible.
- 肿瘤可能性不大, 但是--,- DNA?
- Tumor's less likely, but--,- dna?
肾上腺髓质神经病变测试结果为阴性
Adrenomyeloneuropathy test was negative.
再测一次DNA,试试波罗的海肌阵挛和lafora氏症
Dna test again.Try unverricht-lundborg,and late-onset lafora'S.
遗传病检查太费时了
genetic tests take forever.
你不可能把所想到的,遗传性疾病都测试一遍
You can't just keep testing for every,inherited condition you think it might be.
我当然不能, 我要早点走,但是你们要
Well, not me.I'll be leaving early.,But you guys can.
你身边没人生病,有可能是送外卖的或修理工吗?
You said no one's been sick,,but what about delivery people,repair guy?
我不知道, 我在家工作
I wouldn't know.,I work from home.
一个多月没去办公室了
Haven't been to the office,in over a month.
- 访客?,- 从来没有
- visitors?,- Haven't had any.
最近一周我唯一见过的,就是送皮萨的人
The only person I've seen in the last week,was the pizza delivery guy.
他看起来挺健康
And he looked pretty healthy.
你肯定有一些亲密的人
There's gotta be someone you're close to.
实际上, 我接触最多的人是我父亲
Actually, the person I see most oftenis my father.
- 怎么了?,- 有点想吐
- What is it?,- Just feeling a little nauseous.
- 我想是他的肝脏不行了,- 噢 天哪
- I--I think his liver's failing.,- Oh, god.
那, 是不是意味着我...
Does--does that mean that I'm--
需要中心静脉导管,两袋红血球浓厚液 O阴型
I need a central line kit.,Two units of packed red blood cells,type o negative.
他失去知觉陷入昏迷
He's unconscious and heading for a coma.
已经达到RLA四级昏迷标准
He's at a four on the rlas scale.
暂停所有治疗
Stop all treatment.
你觉得的是药物的副作用?
You think this is a reaction to our meds?
噢 很明显不奏效
Well, they're obviously not helping.
他是个酒鬼,很可能肝脏早就坏了
Given the fact that he's an alcoholic,there's a good chance,his liver wasn't so hot when he came in.
抑制癫痫的药物也可能导致昏迷
Anti-seizure drugs could have,just pushed him over the edge.
我们把药全撤下,怎么维持他的生命?
We take him off those meds,,what do we put him on?
我还以为你知道呢
I was hoping you'd know.
或许理论上行的通,但是我刚给他用上透析仪
May be academic,,but I just started him on dialysis.
肝肾功能的衰竭
Kidney and liver failure.
没多少人能挺过来
Not too many people,come back from that.
看不出有外伤,应该还是感染
trauma's out of the picture.,It could still be infection.
- 要么神经性的,- 要么遗传性的
- Or neurological.,- Or genetic.
我们需要更详细的病史
We needa better history.
你是不是忘记了,病人已经不省人事?
did you miss the part,where the patient lost consciousness?
左旋多巴?
L-dopa?
你不是唤醒Kyle
You're not waking kyle.
你想唤醒他父亲
You're waking his father.
观察力不错
I commend your observational skills.
用药也没法把昏迷的人唤醒
You have no reason to think any amount,of drugs will wake a man from a coma.
植物人, 那就容易多了
Vegetative state.,Much easier.
这个家伙可不是Terri Schiavo,(有争议的安乐死患者)
This guy's no terry schiavo.
他大脑完好, 生命力很强,肌肉也才开始萎缩
His brain's all there.He moves around.,His muscles have barely atrophied.
就等着童话之吻唤醒他呢
Just waitingfor a fairytale kiss.
我吻过他之后,再给他插根针
After I do that,,stick a needle in him.
光是这么大剂量的安非他明,就已经很危险
The amount of amphetamines alone,would be dangerous,
更别说你还加了别的什么破玩意
besides whatever the hell else,you've got in there.
南非有过报道
There are reports out of south africa
一种药物能让人从,植物人状态中短暂苏醒
about a pill that would temporarily revive,someone in a vegetative state.
你我都见过苏醒的病人,太激动人心了
We've all seen awakenings.,Made me cry.
我想哭哭
I wanna cry.
放下注射器
put the syringe down.
我拔枪比你快, 神秘的陌生人
I can out-draw you, mysterious stranger.
我们不能拿个毫无反抗的病人做试验
We don't experiment on helpless patients.
有点理性吧, 这不可能成功
Be reasonable.,There's no way this is gonna work.
就算你唤醒了他, 也持续不了多久
Even if you woke him,,it would only be for a few hours.
一天 最多两天,你是在拿他的生命冒险
A day, two at the most.,You're risking his life.
我冒着被起诉的风险,那才是问题所在
I'm risking getting sued.,That's the only objection here.
你这是在折磨他,和他的家人
You'll be torturing him.,And his family.
从法律上讲,他唯一的亲人躺在楼上快死了
Good news for legal.,The only family he's gotis upstairs dying.
嘿!
Hey!
接下来的24小时我要你们对他全程监护
I want this patient monitored,for the next 24 hours.
找人陪着他以防你折磨死他
I want someonewith him at all times,to make sure you didn't kill him.
到我的办公室来
I want your ass in my office--
天哪, 我饿得要死
god.I'm starving.
我想吃牛排
I could really go for a steak.
你知道自己的名字吗?
do you know your name?
知道你在哪里吗?
You know where you are?
我叫Gabriel Wozniak,但不知道这家医院叫什么
Gabriel wozniak.,I don't know the name of this hospital.
- 三加五等于几?,- 八
- How much are three and five?,- Eight.
还知道乘以二是十六, 乘以四是三十二,是二的三次方
Also known as 1/2 of 16,1/4 of 32,,two to the third power.
真酷
Coolest thing ever.
- 你家里有癫痫史吗?,- 没有
- Any history of seizurein your family?,- No.
- 肝病呢?,- 没有
- Liver disease?,- No.
我来这多久了?
How long have I been here?
我, 我觉得应该,挺长时间了
I--I got the feeling it's,,um,been a long time.
有趣, 你的生物钟还在运行,还有多少意识?
interesting.If your internal clock,kept ticking,how deep does that awareness go?
有没有回想起一些零碎的话语?
Pick up scraps of conversations?
那记得那个穿的象妓女,的医院行政主管吗?
You have the vague sense that the hospital,administrator dresses like a trollop?
最新那部令人倒胃口的星球大战呢?
Or that the new star wars movies,were a disappointment?
我知道我妻子去世了
I know my wife is dead.
就是不知道多久了
I don't know how longit's been.
十年
Ten years.
你记得的最后一见事是什么?
What's the last thingyou remember?
火灾
The fire.
我妻子当时在卧室 她吃了安眠药,我把...
My wife was in the bedroom.,She had takena sleeping pill.I got...
把Kyle抱了出去,再回来救她
kyle out.,Went back in for her.
- 我知道没能救她,- 我很遗憾
- I knew I didn't make it.,- I'm sorry.
你妻子的家族呢?  有癫痫史吗?
What about your wife's side of the family?,Any history of seizures there?
你的儿子Kyle也住进这家医院
Your son kyleis a patient here.
恐怕病情不容乐观
I'm afraid his conditionis serious.
很可能会死的
He may be dying.
我妻子的家里人也没有癫痫病史
No seizure issues on my wife's side, either.
关于牛排的事呢?,怎么没人回答我
What about that steak?,Nobody ever answered me.
咖啡厅里传闻,刻薄的家伙唤醒了昏迷的家伙
Rumor in the cafeteria was,caustic guy was waking up coma guy.
从技术上说, 植物人是被...
Technically,vegetative state guy,was woken by...
- 对 刻薄的人,- 到底怎么了?
- yeah, caustic guy.,- So what happened?
得给他弄份牛排他才会乖乖开口
Gotta get him a steak before I can,ask himany more questions.
他难道不想谈论自己的儿子?
He doesn't want to talkabout his son?
似乎根本没意识到儿子有病
Didn't seem to emotionally register,that his son is sick.
脑部缺氧? 他可是窒息过,还直挺挺的在床上躺了十年呢
Brain issue? He was asphyxiated,,spent ten years as asparagus.
- 谁知道会带来什么损害?,- 很有可能
- Who knows what damageis in there?,- It's possible.
更简单的解释是
'Course, there's alwaysthe simple explanation.
或许他就是不喜欢儿子呢
Maybe he just doesn't like his son.
只有在你的世界里,这才叫简单
Only in your world would that be simple.
抚养儿子的错觉,让他无条件地喷发出无尽的爱
The delusion that fathering a child,installs a permanent geyser of unconditional love--
或许你父亲的爱是有条件的,并不是所有人的...
maybe your father's feelings,were conditional.Not everyone's--
当然 那颠覆了,你对人性本善的幼稚想法
yes, well, of course,that would play,into yourromantic vision of human--
用你能明白的话来说,人类进化出一种本能, 可以为
in terms you would understand,we have an,evolutionary incentiveto sacrifice for our offspring.
自己的后代 部族 朋友的安全作出牺牲
Our tribe,our friends.,Keep them safe.
除了那个不想作出牺牲的人
Except for all the people who don'T.
做任何事都是有条件的
Everything is conditional.
只是有时候条件还没预料的到
You just can't always anticipate the conditions.
介意聊几分钟吗?
Mind if we talk for a few minutes?
你说House医生一天要吃多少颗药来着?
How many pills would you say,dr. House takes a day?
无法给出具体数字
I'm uncomfortable setting a number.
嗯 估计呢
Mm, try.
六颗
Six.
一天里
A day.
他叫你给他...
Has he ever had you...
开过处方吗?
write prescriptions for him?
没有, 你想让我说什么?
No.What is ityou want me to say?
说他吃多了药不能履行医生的职责
That he takes too many pills,and is a danger to the hospital?
还是说他吃得太少,因为他在囤积兜售?
Or he takes too few,because he's selling them on the side?
两者都够荒谬
Either one is ridiculous.
- 我指前者,- 你错了
- I meant the former.,- You're wrong.
我能问问为什么House医生,值得你这样忠心维护?
Can I ask whatdr. House has done,to deserve your loyalty?
他不是个好上司,连个朋友也算不上
He's not knownas a great boss.,He's not even much of a friend.
你看, 他让Wlison医生把责任全揽上身
I mean, look how he left,dr. Wilson holding the bag.
太奇怪了, 你居然不知道
It's odd.,You don't know about that.
你维护他, 但他却什么都不对你说
You defend him, and he won't even,tell you what's happening in his life.
- 呼我来干什么,- 看见你和警察在一起
- I was paged.,- Saw you with a cop.
他想干什么?
What'd he want?
House一天吃多少片 我有没有给他,开过处方, 诸如此类的
How many pills does house take,did I,ever write him a prescription,that sort of stuff.
- 我告诉他六颗,- 一天还是一次?
- I told him six.,- A day,or in a mouthful?
我只希望你们能口径一致
I was just hoping you guys,would stay consistent with--
- 他也想和我们谈谈?,- 轮到你了
- he wants to talkto us, too?,- You're next.
我们得告诉House发生的事
We've gotta tell house what's going on.
- Tritter警官说不能,- 那就不说
- Tritter says no.,- Then no it is.
反正警察会用尽千方百计叫人开口
Cops have a thousand ways,to make life difficult for you.
快说, 小伙子怎么样了?
Quick, what's the kid's status?
我还要赶在冬眠的家伙找,按摩器(情趣用品)之前回去呢
I gotta get back to our sleeper,before he goes looking for the orgasmatron.
如果我是在比喻
See, if that were rhetorical,
我现在可以转身就走,我没有这样做
it would mean that I could just turn around,and leave now.Which I'm not doing.
你们可以推理出结论是...
From which you should deduce--
除了抗生素之外其他的药都撤掉了
he's off all drugs except the antibiotics.
他的肝脏还剩最后一线生机
His liver's just managing to hang in there.
昏迷正在变深
He's still sliding into coma.
你们的理发师真差劲
Your barber sucks.
嗨
Hey.
昏迷节食法,我可真是发财了
Coma diet.,I could makea fortune.
植物人节食法
Vegetative state diet.
- 谁给你的衣服?,- Cuddy医生
- Who gave you your clothes?,- Dr. Cuddy.
我想反正需要些衣服,家当都被烧了
I guess I'll needall new ones anyway.,Everything went in the fire.
哦 别担心
Ah, don't worry about it.
我们现在用的是可再生衣服,穿过一回就吃掉
We use recyclable clothes now.,Wear them once, then eat them.
你儿子的麻疹疫苗
Your son's measles vaccination.
你记得他接种过吗?  哪一种?
Do you remember if he had it,and what type it was?
老兄, 你真够执着,知道吗?
Man, you're a piece of work,you know that?
你不会告诉我的 对吧?
You weren't gonna tell me,were you?
我不需要新衣服,Cuddy医生说我的身体会适应药物
I don't need new clothes.,Dr. Cuddy says my body will adjust to the drugs.
明天又会陷入昏迷
That I'll be a vegetable againby tomorrow.
如果幸运的话, 后天
If I'm really lucky,the day after.
没错
Yeah.
如果我只能再活一天,岂能浪费在医院里受折磨
If I got a day to live,I'm not gonna spend it,in a hospital roombeing grilled.
得了, 你能去哪?
come on, where you gonna go?
你的房子烧光了, 老婆死了,公司卖掉了
Your house burned down.Your wife's dead.,Business was sold off.
你唯一剩下的,就是那个送去作肝组织检查的人
The only thing you have left,is down the hall heading for a liver biopsy.
以前有一家小店
Used to be this little,,um,hole in the wall.
老板叫gian carlo.
Run by a guy named gian carlo.
他做的霍奇三明治是最好的
Made the best hoagies in the world.
用正宗的意式火腿和干酪
Real italian rolls.,Prosciutto. Provolone.
大西洋城离这里多远?
How far is atlantic city from here?
你只能活一天,就想要个三明治?
You have one day to live.,And you want a sandwich.
- 死刑犯都可以吃最后的早餐,- 政府提供的
- People on death row get a last meal.,- State provides it.
谁给你提供?,你有车吗? 有钱吗?
Who's providing for you?,You got a car? Money?
你在跟我讲条件
You're negotiating with me.
帮我多取100
Take out another hundred for me.
我还要你的车
And I need your car.
我不想帮你
I'm not doing you any favors.
明天就还给你,最多两天, 公路旅行
You'll get it back tomorrow.,Two days, max.,Road trip.
这就像控制天气一样没谱,我希望你别在车里吃
This is like trying to control the weather,,but I'd prefer it if you didn't eat in the car.
- 我刚做过养护,- 我开车
- I just had it detailed.,- I drive.
- 这不可能,- 可以
- Oh, the hell he does.,- Sure.
这家伙刚从植物人状态醒过来,而且也没驾照
Aside from the fact he just woke upfrom a,vegetative state,the guy doesn't have a licensE.
这样办吧,被警察抓到, 我们就撒谎
How 'bout this?,Cops stop us, we lie.
你反正也做过了,接着
You know how to do that.,Chips.
他的血液里全是药
It's all the drugs,pumping through his system.
现在他的反射速度,快过小dale earnhardt(著名赛车手)
Right now, his reflexes,are better than dale earn hardt jr.'S.
嘿, 这是什么?,上面写着I-POD
Hey, what's this?,It says, "ipp-odd."
我来了
I'm coming.
说说环境中的毒物吧
so let's talk about toxic exposure.
以前的颜色有什么不好?,我喜欢棕色的
what was wrong with the old colors?,I trusted brown.
紫色的里面也是巧克力么?
Do the purple ones,have chocolate inside?
树莓可卡因
Raspberry cocaine.
被烧掉的房子在哪?
This house that burned down.,Where was it?
Moorestown 新泽西
Moorestown, new jersey.
我需要知道这糖豆的成分,因为我对莓类过敏
Listen, I really need to know about the candy,because I'm allergicto berries.
- 你没说起过,- 很重要吗?
- You didn't mention that.,- Is it significant?
不
No.
你还在哪里住过?,所有地方, 包括度假场所
So where else did you live?,List everywhere,including vacations.
从你老婆怀孕开始讲起
Start with when your wife got pregnant.
我们原来住新泽西,后来从新泽西搬到新泽西
We lived in jersey.,Then we moved to jersey.From there, jersey.
你想听到什么?
What are you waiting to hear?
亚马逊丛林里蚊虫飞舞的小别墅?,含铅涂料的墙壁?
About the little cottage in the amazon,with the mosquitoes and the lead paint all over the walls?
是的
Yes.
知道吗?
You know what?
我让你跟来,不是让你毁掉我仅的一天快乐
I didn't let you come along so you could,suck all the fun out of my one day of life.
算你不走运,这正是本人的目的
Well, you're outta luck,,'cause that's totally why I'm here.
好吧, 规则改变
Okay.,Rule change.
出钱的人制定规则
Person with the money makes the rules.
在本例中, 是出钱者的朋友制定规则
Or in this case,the person who's friends,with the person with the money makes the rules.
你想要答案,更甚于我想要钱
Well, you want answers,more than I want money.
好吧, 那我们这么玩,问我什么都可以
All right, so here's the game.,Ask whatever you want.
你每回答我一个问题,就可以得到一个答案
But for every question I answer,,you have to answer one first.
我能回答什么令你感兴趣的东西?
And why would you care about,anything I have to say?
我死前是个成功人士
The day before I died,,I was a successful man.
我的工厂雇员超过200人
I had a factory with over 200 employees.
我说话大家都得听,我喜欢权势
People listened when I talked.,I liked power.
现在我唯一的权力,是不让你顺心
Now the only power I have left,is the power to annoy you.
请wilson的助手喝咖啡
Took wilson's assistant for coffee.
- 为什么?,- Tritter说的
- Why?,- Something tritter said.
她说警察怀疑House偷走Wilson的处方本,并伪造他的签名
She told me the police think that house stole,wilson's prescription pad and forged his name.
你相信?
You...believe it?
- 你呢?,- 我绝对信
- Do you?,- Oh, absolutely.I do.
只是看看你到底有多天真
I'm just checking,how naive you are.
他不会偷处方本,危及好友的职业生涯
He's not gonna steal his best friend's pad,j,eopardize his career.
除非他的好友对他说不
Until his best friend says no to him.
House是个瘾君子
house is a junkie.
瘾君子为了得到药,什么都会做
Junkies do whatever they,have to do to get what they need.
Kyle进入三级昏迷了
Kyle's down to a three on the rlas scale.
只剩一些基本反射
He's only showing localized response.
我找House,告诉他时间不多了
I'll call house.,Tell him we're gonna need an answer soon.
到右边车道, 换295号公路,巧克力棒给我
Get in your right lane for 295.,And pass me the twizzlers.
- 我很好奇,- 不, 你才不
- I'm curious.,- No, you're not.
为什么一个人的第一反应,是驾车远离他唯一的亲人?
Why would a man's first instinct be,to drive away from the only family he's got?
不! 没时间搞你那些情感戏
No!This is no time for you to do your thing.
我们不在乎他的精神状态,不在乎他是否快乐
We don't care about his state of mind.,We don't care if he's happy.
你的工厂是做什么的?
This factory of yours.,What did you make?
- 问我一个问题,- 正在想
- So ask me a question.,- I'm thinking.
只剩6颗了
Only six left, by the way.
签我的名就可以了,你不需要医生, 只需要一支笔
So sign my name.,You don't need a doctor.You need a pen.
你们俩有什么过节?
What is upwith you two?
Wilson对警察撒谎,以免我坐牢
Wilson lied to the bulls,to keep me out of the big house.
- 你是不是疯了?,- 怎么, 他能跟谁说?
- Are you out of your mind?,- Well, who's he gonna tell?
明天晚上, 他又会变成,没思想的活死人
By tomorrow night,he's gonna,bea mindless stalk of celery.
既然我刚才回答了你,现在该我问了
Since I answered that one,,by the way,my turn.
- 你的工厂生产什么?,- 豪华游船
- What did you make in your factory?,- Luxury boats.
- 你曾经相爱过?,- 哇
- Have you ever been in love?,- Wow.
真会找问题,知道这里有隐情
Going right for the closets,with the embarrassing stuff.
我爱过,请描述船只
Good move.Yes.,Describe the boats.
船体35至65英尺, 双引擎,木地板舱室 超大床铺
35- to 65-foot hulls.Twin engines,parquet floors,in the galleys,staterooms with queen beds.
- 你们怎么相遇的?,- 她向我开枪
- How'd you meet?,- She shot me.
这些船, 应该用的是防霉油漆?
These boats.I assume you used,mildew-resistant painton the hulls?
这是自然,开枪打你?
Naturally.,Shot you?
彩弹枪,医生对律师
Paintball.,Doctors versus lawyers.
- 你有没有带儿子去工厂?,- 当然有
- You ever take your son to the factory?,- Sure.
他到处乱跑,不过都是安全的
He used to run all over the place,,but it was perfectly safe.
还爱上过别人吗?
Ever love anybody else?
不能再问了,我已经得到答案
No more questions.,I got my answer.
爸爸在办公,儿子就去看喷漆
While dad's in the office,,son's watching them spray-paint.
小孩子会戴口罩吗?
And what kid wears a mask?
水银损害中枢神经
Mercury specifically targets,the central nervous system.
你说这是我的错?
Are you sayingthis was my fault?
水银中毒解释了癫痫
Mercury poisoning explains the seizures.
肝脏就像水槽的过滤网
The liver is likea big soup strainer.
水流下去了,脏东西留在网上
Soup runs through.,Chicken dumplings stay.
水指的是血液,脏东西就是...
For soup, read blood.,For chicken dumplings--
我知道 我知道,水银
I get it, I get it.,Mercury.
本来还可以支撑,直到你儿子大量酗酒
Sits more or less idle until your kid,pours tequila shooters into his liver.
肝脏完蛋了, 肾脏也就保不住,一切都得到解释
When the liver goes,takes out the kidneys.,Explains everything.
是我, Foreman, 抽血做水银中毒检测
Yeah, it's me.Foreman, draw blood.,Test for mercury poisoning.
Chase, 等结果的时候,按照重金属螯合疗法治疗
Chase.Start heavy metal chelation,while we're waiting for results.
Chase不在, 我这就...
Chase isn't here.,I'll start the--
他在哪?
where is he?
实验室
The lab.
- 他每天吃几粒药?,- 很难讲
- How many pills does he take a day?,- It's hard to say.
疼痛程度不一样,可能是6, 8或10
Pain levels vary over time.,Could be six, eight, ten.
给他开过处方吗?
Ever write any prescriptions for him?
- 是的,- 为什么? 他让你写的?
- Yes.,- Why? Did he tell you to?
他请求我写的
He asked me to.
医学这个行业常常能,吸引一些热衷权势的人
Medicine...attracts people,who are attracted to power.
我知道House很讨厌,听到病人的不同意见
I know how he hates when he is defied by a patient.
同样他也不太可能,容忍下属的反对
I doubt he handles defiance,from his staff any better.
说错了请纠正我
Now, you correct meif I'm wrong.
我认为House医生不会请求
But I don't think dr. House asks for anything.
他只会索取
I think he takes it.
而且我认为你为了替他圆谎,将陷入困境...
And I think that you are stuck lying,to the police to cover up something...
违心地做一件你不想做的事
you didn't want to do.
我们像玩大富翁一样,在圣詹斯大街转了几个来回
we have been up and down st.James,like a monopoly car.
不在这里,Gian carlo已经搬走了
It's not here.,Giancarlo has left the building.
我们还可以调头回普林斯顿
We could still turn around,and go back to princeton.
不, 我们走了这么远,我一定要吃到三明治
No!We've come this far.,I'm getting the hoagie.
如果你儿子确实汞中毒,治疗会有效果
If your son does have mercury poisoning,,there's a good chance he'll respond to the chelation.
也许你能在他全面衰竭之前,见他最后一面
You might be able to have,a few minutes with him before you lapse.
你这么关心我做什么?
Why are you so concerned about me?
wilson的内心深处以为,如果他关爱别人, 他就不会死
Deep inside, wilson believes that,if he cares enough,he'll never have to die.
- 你的行为不正常,- 你懂什么叫正常?
- Your behavior isn't normal.,- And you would know normal.
他到底做了什么?,十年了仍无法原谅他?
What could he have done that you won't forgive,after ten years,when this is your last chance?
我儿子注定变成那样
My son is what he is.
他母亲那边全是酗酒的失败者
His mother's side?,All drunken losers.
他走的也是这条路
He's gone the same way.
House告诉你,你儿子喝酒损坏了肝
House told you that drinking,had damaged your son's liver.
我刚说过
I just said that.
但你离开医院之前并不知情
But you didn't hear him say that,till after we left the hospital.
你为什么离开?
So why did you leave?
也许你儿子继承的是你这边的
maybe your son takes after your side.
- 癫痫和对感情过敏,- 好了好了, 说够了
- Seizures and an allergy to emotional connections.,- Okay, okay, okay.Enough.
我们在大西洋城,我还有时间
We're in atlantic city,,and my time's not up yet.
找一间带赌场的酒店
We'll find a hotel with a casino.
血压下降
Bp's starting to drop.
血气降到70
O2-sat's down to 70.
0.3毫克肾上腺素
0.3 milligrams of epi in.
你干什么?,让他出血更快?
What are you trying to do?,Make him bleed faster?
检查脉搏
Check the pulse.
不是肝脏的问题
It's not his liver.
是心脏
It's the heart.
我知道他是做法式菜的,但我相信他能做这个
I understand he's a french chef,,but I'm sure he can handle this.
用12寸意大利面包,牛至叶醋
We need a 12-inch italian roll,,oregano vinegar--
不, 不是葡萄醋,牛至叶醋
no.Not balsamic vinegar.,Oregano vinegar.
等价交换, clarice,继续我们的游戏
Quid pro quo, clarice.,Game's still on.
我以为答案是汞中毒
I thought the answer was mercury poisoning.
除此之外你还想知道什么?
What other questions would you care about?
如果你们都只能活一天,你会要求最后的一餐
If you each had one day to live,,you'd lookfor one last meal,
House则要最后的答案
and house would lookfor,one last answer.
不, 能不能就把原料送过来?
No, can you just send,the ingredients up here?
我自己做
And I'll make it myself.
过去的10年里,你有多少意识?
Last ten years.,How much awareness did you have?
不知道,我只知道时间不短
I don't know.,I knew it wasn'tthe next day.
我知道,我能记得你的声音
I--I knew that--,I recognized your voice.
你多久到我病房里来一次?
How often were you in my room?
不, 你浪费了一个问题
No.You're wasting a question.
我有更好的问题
I have a better one.
- 为什么偷我的处方本?,- 哦, 老天, 你是对的
- Why steal my pad?,- oh, my god.You're right.
我是瘾君子,谢谢你让我认清自己
I'm an addict.,Thanks for opening my eyes.
不, 我是说,为什么偷我的?
No, I mean, why my pad?
Foreman, cameron还有chase的,都可以偷
Foreman, cameron, and chase's pads,are just as convenient.
但他们和你的关系并非自主,他们是你的手下
But their association with you,is involuntary.They're employees.
我是通过自主选择和你联系在一起
I associate with you through choice.
任何牵涉自主选择的关系,你都要看看对方能容忍的底线
And any relationship that involves choice,you have to seehow far you can push before it breaks.
这个问题省心
This is easy.
你自问自答,答完后还做点心
You ask the questions,answer them,,and make tasty snacks.
我们去赌场试试运气
Let's go try the casino.
有一天, 我们的友谊会破裂
And one day,our friendship will break.
然后又证明你的对,友谊是有条件的
And that'll just prove your theory,that relationships are conditional,
你不需要和别的人类有关系,也不配拥有
and you don't need,human connection,or deserve it,
或是其它潜藏在,你那迷宫一样的大脑里的东西
or whatever goes on in that,rat maze of your brain.
对不起,如果早知道他这么烦人
Sorry.If I'd known,he was gonna be this annoying,
我会偷Cameron的处方本,偷Foreman的车
I would've stolen dr. Cameron's pad,and dr. Foreman's car.
至少她懂得欣赏我令人深思的忧郁
At least she appreciates my brooding melancholy.
House倾诉热线,请讲述您的苦闷
House's house of whining.,State your complaint.
- 血压直线下降,- 做心脏超声
- Patient's bp just dropped like a stone.,- Do an echo.
- 水银不太可能造成如此...,- 确实
- Mercury isn't likely to damage--,- it didn'T.
汞中毒阴性
Mercury test was negative.
做心脏超声
Do an echo.
我错了, 你儿子仍然要死
I was wrong.,Your son's still dying.
我要知道你所有亲属的病
I need to go over every relative,you ever had again.
不用说病了,直接说怎么死的
This time, forget their diseases.,Just tell me how they died.
没时间相互问了
We don't have time to take turns.
告诉我答案,最后你可以问我一个大问题
Gimme the answers.,You get a big one at the end.
问什么都可以,涉及什么隐私, 尊严都可以
You go for whatever you want.,Destroy my privacy,my dignity.
- 你祖母?,- 中暑, 独立日野餐
- your grandmother?,- Heat exhaustioN. Fourth of july picnic.
她活了92岁
The woman was 92.
厨房有谁知道,以前在圣詹斯的一家三明治店?
Does anyone in the kitchen know the hoagie shop,that used to be on st.James place?
有糖尿病的小姨子
Your sister-in-lawwith the diabetes.
- 据你所致还活着吗?,- 死了
- As far as you know,is she still alive?,- She's not.
看完费城队比赛,回家的时候车祸死亡
Killed in a traffic accident,driving homefrom a phillies game.
我相信一定喝了很多啤酒,费城队输了
I'm sure a lot of beer was consumed.,Phillies lost.
- 你父亲?,- 衰老, 心脏衰竭了
- Your father?,- Old age.Heart finally gave out.
- 你岳父?,- 交通肇事逃逸
- Your wife's father?,- Hit-and-run.
出去遛一条不听话的狗
Walking the incontinent dog.
嗨, 你们送外卖吗?
Uh, hi.,Do you guys deliver?
这么说吧, 如果你送货,我出100块小费
Let me put it this way.If you deliver,,there'll be a $100 tip in it for you.
棒极了!,胜利
Excellent!,Victory.
哈哈, 这个夜晚终于开始顺心了
Ha, ha, the night isfinally going my way.
Wilson, 给我一罐汽水
Wilson, toss me a soda.
我们找个地方谈谈?
Shall we go somewhereto talk?
House是个混蛋,但他确实需要止疼药
House is an ass.,But he obviously needs pain medication.
一个人感觉到多少疼痛,不由政府说了算
How much pain one person feels,is not a call the government should be making.
你认为我是个带警徽的官僚,依照某些死板规则做事
So you think I'm a bureaucrat with a badge,following some arbitrary guideline.
- 是的,- 噢
- Yeah.I do.,- Oh.
你是说我应该信任他,是吗?
So you're saying I should...,just trust him.Do you?
- 你不是这方面专业人士...,- 我觉得你也不是
- You're not qualified to make that--,- I'm not sure you are,either.
我当差20年, 每天都有人
I've been a cop for 20 years,and not a day,goes by that someone doesn't try to
试图给我编故事
sell me someself-serving story.
如果你做我的工作,你会明白
If you had my job,you'd know.
人都会撒谎
Everybody lies.
所有亲戚都说完了
Think you've run out of relatives.
那么, 该我了
So.,It's my turn.
你为什么做医生?
Why did you become a doctor?
这就是你的大问题?
That's the big question?
我给你机会羞辱我,你就问出这种问题?
I gave you complete license to humiliate me,,and that's the best you can do?
好吧, 我们来谈谈神奇的人体
Well, okay.Let's discuss,the wonder of the human body.
不不不, 你是好奇的人
No, no, no.,You're a curious guy.
你喜欢找到答案,为什么不去做研究?
You like to figure things out.,Why not go into research?
为什么给人治病?,明显你憎恨人
Why work with people when you...,obviously hate people?
恋母情结
Oedipal fixation.
我希望得到母亲的爱,她觉得ben casey(医生肥皂剧)是最棒的...
I was seeking my mother's love,and she thought,that ben casey was just the dreamiest--
好啊, 你觉得不需要再问我什么了?
okay, fine.You don't think you'll need,any more answers from me?
来点真的
Give me a hard time.
我14岁时, 我父亲驻扎日本
When I was 14,my father was stationed in japan.
我和学校的孩子去攀岩
I went rock climbing with this kid from school.
他摔伤了, 我送他去医院
He fell, he got injured,,and I had to bring him to the hospital.
我们走错了门,经过大厅里一个人的身边
We came in through the wrong entrance,and passed this guy in the hall.
是个清洁工
It was a janitor.
我朋友感染了,医生们束手无策
My friend came down with an infection,and the doctors didn't know what to do.
所以他们找来了那个...清洁工
So they brought in...,the janitor.
他曾经是医生
He was a doctor.
还是"布拉库"
And a buraku.
日本的贱民阶层
One of japan's untouchables.
他的祖先都是屠夫, 掘墓人
His ancestors had been,slaughterers,gravediggers.
这个人知道他不会被同僚所接受
And this guy,he knew that,he wasn't accepted by the staff.
甚至不做尝试,他不修边幅
Didn't even try.,He didn't dress well.
甚至没有伪装一下
He didn't pretend to be one of them.
医院的管理者也不觉得他有什么用处
The people that ran that place,,they didn't think that he had anything they wanted.
除了需要他的时候
Except when they needed him.
因为他是对的
Because he was right.
其它的一切都不重要了
Which meant that nothing else mattered.
必须听他的
And they had to listen to him.
谢谢
Thank you.
准备20毫克地西泮
Need 20 milligram sof diazepam in a syringe.
心跳不规则加速
Heart beat's irregularand accelerating.
- 升到200,- 他会衰竭的
- It's at 200.,- He's gonna crash.
- 地西泮的过敏反应?,- 最好不是
- Allergic reactionto the diazepam?,- Better hope so.
要么是过敏,要么就是他的心脏完蛋了
It's either that,or his heart's done.
着火那天晚上发生什么事了?
What happened on the night of the fire?
是啊, 肯定有一段痛苦的回忆
Yeah, I'm sure it's a,stressful emotional question.
老实回答
Suck it up.
我妻子吃了安眠药就上床了,那是圣诞夜
My wife had takena sleeping pill,and gone to bed.It was christmas eve.
我让kyle在壁炉边做爆米花,结果他...
I let kyle pop corn in the fireplace.,He managed to...
把壁炉柴砸碎了
knock loose some tinder.
包装纸烧着了
Wrapping paper caught on fire.
火势蔓延很快,我把kyle弄出来
Spread.So fast.,I got kyle out.
再进去救--
And when I went back in for--
你真可悲
you're a disappointment.
你表现得好像不需要任何人
You act as though,you don't need anybody.
你怪儿子酿成这起事故
You--you just blame your son,for what happened.
我不怪他, 他才12岁
I don't blame him.,He was a 12-year-old boy.
不能拿意外来责怪小孩子
You don't blame a kid for an accident.
那我们来这里干什么?,干嘛不在他身边?
Then what are we doing here?,Why aren't you with him?
在身边又怎么样!
Because it wouldn't matter!
我没能保住我的家人!
I failed to keep my family safe!
我没能扑灭火,没能救出我妻子
I couldn't stop the fire.,I couldn't save my wife!
现在, 你又要让我目睹,我无法救回儿子
Now you want meto stick around watching,while I fail to save my son.
多谢你把我弄醒
Thank you so much for waking me up.
你儿子怎么砸碎壁炉柴?
How did your son dislodge the tinder?
烤爆米花的托盘掉落
He dropped the popcorn tray.
他说了那很重,我早该留意的
He had been complaining it was too heavy.,I should've listened.
遛狗被车撞
And the hit-and-run.,Walking the pissy dog.
- 是晚上的事?,- 是的, 怎么了?
- That happen at night?,- I think so, yeah.Why?
输球后的车祸,也是晚上的比赛?
Car accident after the phillies lost.,Night game?
肌纤维粗红病,这是遗传病
Ragged red fiber.,It's an inherited condition.
掉东西, 肌肉无力, 夜视能力差
Dropping things, muscle weakness.,Poor night vision.
导致协调性差,易出事, 不小心
Makes people seem uncoordinated,,accident-prone,careless.
是在线粒体DNA上的
It's transmittedin mitochondrial dna.
所以只能从母亲这一边继承
So it only passes through the mother.
你妻子的家族并非酒鬼,他们有病
Your wife's family weren't drunks.,They were sick.
- 不会影响肝脏,- 这孩子是个酒鬼
- It wouldn't have affected his liver.,- The kid is a drunk.
他以为自己杀死母亲,让父亲变成植物人
He thinks that he killed his mother,and turned his father into a vegetable.
要是我, 可能也会来几杯
You know, I might have a few shots myself.
- Foreman.,- 检查DNA, 看有无肌纤维粗红病
- Foreman.,- Test his dna for ragged rediber.
- 不会有什么...,- 这么想
- It's not gonna--,- here's a thought.
能否不要先假定检查不出,直到做完再说话?
Why don't we not assume that the test,is negative until we actually do it?
House.,这孩子有严重的心肌病
House.,The kid has severe cardiomyopathy.
酗酒者,不可能得到心脏移植
Alcoholic.,No shot at a transplant.
也许能搞清楚为什么,能满足你, 但是...
So yeah, maybe you figured out why.,Good for you, but...
他还是一样要死
he's gonna die anyway.
我要把我的心脏给kyle
I want to give kyle my heart.
这个病, 不管它叫什么,只从母亲一边遗传, 我的心脏是好的
This thing--whatever it is--,you said he gets it from the mother.My heart's fine.
你的心脏也许还能,在你体内工作多年
And it could go on being fine,for the rest of your life.
是啊, 他要了也不怎么用
yeah.It's not like,he's gonna do anything with it.
你弄醒他一次
Well, you woke him up once.
也许别人能找出其它办法
Maybe someone will come up,with some other answer.
有些医学突破是很出人意料的
We've both seen breakthroughs,no one expected.
肌纤维粗红病可以治疗,但不可能治愈
And ragged red fiber's treatable,,but not curable.
就算他得到你的心脏,也不保证能活
Even if he gets your heart,,there's no guarantee.
他是我儿子
He's my kid.
不, 你以为我会同意吗?
No.Did you really expect,a different answer?
以前也有过,在病人濒死的时候安排移植
We have arranged transplants before,when a patient is near death.
他不是濒死
Except he isn't near death.
他说"杀死我, 把我的心剖出来"
He's saying,"kill me,and cut out my heart."
你脑筋出问题了?
Are you out of your mind?
好吧, 我想想其它办法
Fine.,I'll think of something else.
对不起
I'm sorry.
Wilson, 出去
Wilson.,Get out.
不
No.
你为我在警察面前撒了很多谎
You've lied to the cops enough for me.
也许我并不想逼迫你,直到关系破裂
Maybe I don't wanna,push this till it breaks.
吃药最近但
Pills are the simplest.
上吊不容易损伤心脏
Hanging has less chance of damaging the heart.
我不怕疼
I'm okay with pain.
勒死比颈部折断好一些
Strangulation is better than breaking your neck.
这意味这着过程很缓慢
Which means this'll be slow.
就算我们现在一路超速赶回去
I wouldn't get to see him,even if we got in the car right now
也见不到他了, 是吗?
and broke the speed limit driving back,would I?
是的
No.
告诉他
Tell him-
我不知道告诉他什么
I don't knowwhat to tell him.
该轮到我问问题了, 是吗?
Think it's my turn to ask a question, isn't it?
不是
I don't think so.
你刚问了那个超速的问题
'Cause you just asked me that thing,about the speed limit.
你想知道什么?
What do you wanna know?
如果你父亲能跟你说话,你想听到什么?
If if you could hear one thing,from your father,what would it be?
- 对你没用的,- 不妨一试
- It wouldn't help you.,- Try me.
我想要他说...
I'd want him to say...
"你是对的, 做得对"
"You were right.,You did the right thing."
确实没用
Yeah.,It doesn't help.
- 嘿,- 嘿
- Hi.,- Hi.
- 我是Wilson医生,- 我是Schaeffer太太
- I'm dr. Wilson.,- I'm mrs. Schaeffer.
我从普林斯顿来
I'm from princeton.
我们夫妻和三个孩子住在费城
My husband and i and our,three children live in philadelphia.
那么...你想不想出轨?
So, uh...,do you like to swing?
不
No.
好吧, 如果你改变主意, 我就在...
Well, if you change your mind,I'm in--
house.House!,是622号还是642号房?
house.House!,Is it room 622? 642?
- 622.,- 622.
好
Yeah.
- 不在场证明,- 我知道
- Alibi.,- I figured.
他身边有一瓶打开的阿司匹林
They found an open bottle,of aspirin by the body.
幸亏他有头痛
Lucky he had a headache.
心脏在运输过程中保全很好
Reduced trauma to the heart in transit.
幸亏
Lucky.
不可能就这些
That can't be all.
你得到了他的心脏
Well, you got a heart out of it.
你还想要多少器官?
How many organs do you want from the guy?
我是说, 我父亲肯定说过什么
I mean,my father must have said something.
不可能就这样...,他一定让你带了什么话
He couldn't just--he must have given you,some kind of a message for me.
他说你是对的,你做得对
He said you were right.,You did the right thing.
我什么是对的?
Right about what?
什么意思?
What does that mean?
我怎么知道?,他是你爸
How would I know?,He's your dad.
你知道这个病例有趣在哪里?
You know what I found,interesting about this case?
证明人与人之间可以有无条件的爱,尽管你还是不相信
That it proved that people can love unconditionally,,and you can tell yourselfit's not true,
却在大西洋城的一家酒店,让另一个人剖出自己的心脏?
but you'll just end up in a hotel room,in atlantic city asking someone to cut your heart out?
三明治
The hoagie.
你知道这个人只是用三明治
You thought this guy was emotionally,confused and that the hoagiewas just a mask
掩饰他对儿子的感情
to hide his real feelingstowards his son.
是的
It was.
你知道你不在的时候,Tritter跟你的手下谈过话?
Did you know tritter was talking,to your team while we were away?
知道
Yeah.
你还是竭尽所能,用蛋黄酱和意式火腿, 帮他做面具
And yet you moved heaven and earth,to get him that mask with mustard and prosciutto.
- 谁告诉你的?,- 他们都说了
- Which one of them told you?,- All of them.
这表明他们都没有说什么对我不利的
Which means that none of them,said anythingI have to worry about.
回到三明治
Back to the hoagie.
你以为我的依赖性已经失控
You think that my addiction's out of hand.
你太想被人需要
Your need to be needed is so strong
所以你给别人他们想要的,他们需要的, 他们自以为需要的
that you'll give people what they want,,what they need,what they think they need.
我的助人没什么可指摘的
I don't think my enablingis anything,you should be complaining about.
我是James wilson医生,帐号835687
Yes, my nameis dr. James wilson.,Accot number 835687.
ATM说我余额为零
The atm says I've got zero--
什么意思? 冻结?
what does that mean--a hold?
好的, 谢谢,Thanks.
Yeah, okay.,Thanks.
为了警方调查需要,我的帐户被冻结
My accounts have been frozen,as part of a police investigation.
他们不能永远扣住你的钱
They can't keep your money forever.
确实不能, 他们可以一直扣到,我愿意指证你去做10年牢
No, they can keep it till I agree,to help send you to prison for ten yearS.
晚饭靠你了
You're getting dinner.